Nakimuli Mary Susan

Software Engineer

One of the many sectors that technology has profoundly impacted is the health industry, which has seen tremendous breakthroughs. Technology, for instance, helps experts acquire and analyze information so they can give communities better health care. Given the alternatives that have been explored, there has been a notable gap in offering ideal circumstances for preterm infants' survival. As a Software Engineer,. Susan is certain that she can put revolutionary ideas into practice to lower the rate of preterm infant mortality because of her technical skills and abilities.

nakimulimarysusan@gmail.com

Karen, Nairobi, Kenya

github.com/NakimuliSusan

+256706112100

in linkedin.com/in/nakimuli-mary-susan-4a1447223

EDUCATION

codeHive

Diploma in Information Technology

02/2022 - 12/2022

Nairobi , Kenya

- Back-end development (Python, Django) - Object Oriented Programming with classes, Creating URL routing models, Django as Python Framework.
- Frontend web development (HTML/Css, JavaScript) -ReactJS as a Javascript Framework, Scopes and Hoisting, DOM manipulation DOM event and handlers, Rest Apis in Nodejs
- UI/UX Design (Figma,Adobe Illustrator) - Building low and high fidelity wireframes,Principles of design,Creating user friendly journeys of a product.
- Mobile development (Kotlin) - Working with collections like Array Adapters, API Testing with Postman, Constraint layouts, accessing widgets in code, Firebase Authentication.
- Internet of Things Creating electronic circuits with arduino boards , Fusion 360 to visualize hardware products, Design Thinking .
- UX Research Design thinking process, Compiling desk research into reports.

National Certificate in Electrical Engineering Nakawa Vocational Training College

02/2017 - 11/2018

Kampala . Uaanda

- Industrial Automation
- Domestic Installation
- Machine maintenance
- Air conditioning and Refrigeration

WORK EXPERIENCE

Electrical Engineer Intern

Roofings Rolling Mills Limited

12/2021 - 01/2022

03/2023 - 06/2023

Kampala, Uganda

- Working hand in hand with the Electrical department of the plant.
- Maintenance of small electrical circuits.

Software Developer Intern

637 Capital Limited

Nairobi , Kenya

- Working with javascript frameworks and libraries such as React, Typescript, Node, Next js to create web applications.
- Using Redux for glbal state management
- Project management

SKILLS

Great understanding of using collaborative and version control software like Git.

Database systems such as SQL

Ability to write SQL queries

Knowledge in Django as a backend framework

Creating Diango Restful API's.

Redux for global state management

Knowledge of creatins scalable web applications in .NET

Proficient in applying Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) principles in ASP.NET development

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Todo list web application (06/2022 - Present)

 A todo list web application created using Vue.Js a Javascript Framework. Github link: https://github.com/NakimuliSusan/To-do-list----Vue.is.git

Gym Mobile Application (05/2022 - Present)

 A gym web mobile to help users who workout to track and plan their gym activities as they keep healthy and fit. Developed using Kotlin. https://github.com/NakimuliSusan/WorkoutLog.git

Quicklab (10/2022 - 12/2022)

- This react -Django application helps students to boost their performance in science subjects while practicing on guided practicals
- **GithubLink** https://github.com/akirachix/cheche/tree/feature/signup
- Web app link https://quick-lab.netlify.app/

SQL-Queries (02/2022 - Present)

 This project helps me learn more about sql queries. Githublinkhttps://github.com/NakimuliSusan/SQL.git

CERTIFICATES

Code Queen Web development Bootcamp - Educating The Children (06/2021 - 10/2021)

Certificate in Basic HTML/Css and JavaScript.

REFERENCES

Linda Kamau Co-Founder and Managing director AkiraChix lkamau@akirachix.com

John Owuor, Trainer Senior Software Engineer Twiga Foods owuor91@gmail.com